proguitartuner.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | Pro Guitar

## 1 Introduction

Pro Guitar provides a platform, including a website available at www.proguitar.com and related mobile applications, which makes available various services, (the “Service” or “Services”).

In this Privacy Policy [“Pro Guitar”, “JR Innovation”, “we”, “us”, “ours”] refers to JR Innovation AB. Please read this document in conjunction with our [Terms of Service](https://www.proguitar.com/about/policies/terms "Terms of Service") and our [Cookies Policy](https://www.proguitar.com/about/policies/cookies "Cookies Policy").

We respect your privacy concerns and we are committed to protect your personal Information as that term is defined as (“Information”). We aim to maintain consistently high levels of best practice in our processing of your Information.

This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you how we gather, use and disclose your personal data. This Policy is intended to assist you in making informed decisions about your Information when using the Services provided by us. Please take a few moments to read and understand the Privacy Policy.

By using this website and/or our services you consent to our collection and use of your Information as described in this document. If we change our Privacy Policy and/or procedures, we will update this Policy to keep you aware of what Information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Your continued use of the website or services after this Privacy Policy has been amended shall be deemed to be your continued acceptance of the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, as amended. We encourage you to bookmark this web page and review this Privacy Policy regularly.

In addition to this Privacy Policy, each service offered by us or our partners may have additional privacy provisions that are specific to the particular service. These supplemental disclosures are made adjacent to the particular service at the time your Information is collected.

## 2 Information we collect automatically

When you use this Service, certain non-personally identifying information is recorded automatically by the standard operation of our Internet servers. Information such as the type of browser being used, its operating system, and your computer's Internet Protocol (“IP”) address (a number that your Internet service provider assigns to your computer whenever you surf the Internet) is gathered in order to facilitate our online operations and to assure an efficient online experience for you. If you access our Service from a mobile or other device, we may collect information for that device (including operating system, browser, type of device) is gathered in order to facilitate our mobile operations and to assure an efficient mobile experience for you. We may use or share this information for security purposes, to generate group statistics about our user community, or as required by law.

For example, Pro Guitar may collect and store some or all of the following information provided by the social network:

  * your first and last name
  * your profile picture or its URL
  * your social network ID number (like your Facebook ID number), which is linked to publicly-available information like your name and profile photo
  * the social network ID numbers and other public data for your friends
  * the login e-mail you provided to that social network when you registered with it
  * your physical location and that of the devices you use to access our Services
  * your gender
  * your birthday and/or age range
  * other publicly-available information on the social network, and/or
  * any other information that you or the social networks share with Pro Guitar.

If you access our Service from a social network, you should also read that social network’s Terms of Service and Privacy Policy.

## 3 Information you voluntarily provide to us

We collect and maintain Information that you voluntarily submit to us during your use of our Services. For example:

  * When you register on our website, for a product or other service, you may provide us with certain Information including your name, email address, user name, password and demographic Information
  * If you sign up to our service via a social network we may use the profile Information you enable us to access regarding your interests.
  * If you sign up to receive a newsletter, a magazine, enter a competition or participate in social networking activities, you may provide us with contact Information (e.g., email, telephone and/or or physical address)
  * You may provide us with Information in the course of email, customer support interactions and surveys.

Information you provide to us will be held in a database using reasonable security measures to protect the data from unauthorized access. Different services operated by us may ask for different pieces of Information. You can choose not to provide us with certain Information, but this may stop you from gaining access to a service or limit the features that you can use on our websites. For more Information, please see the “How We Use Your Information” section of the Policy below. 

## 4 Protection of children's personal information

4.1 Most of our sites are not designed for children, but one or two may receive visits by children and young people under the age of 16 and we encourage them to speak to their parents before submitting any personal Information on any of our sites.

4.2 We recommend that parents or guardians supervise young people while they are online.

4.3 We are dedicated to the protection of children’s and young people’s personal Information and we do not knowingly market to children.

3.4 If you are under 16 years of age you should always ask your parent or guardian before:

  * Responding to anything on any of our sites
  * Asking us to send anything to you or another young person
  * Enter a competition or a game online – you must generally be over 16 years of age to enter, but please do check the specific Terms & Conditions for each instance.
  * Post anything on a bulletin board or any chat room
  * Offer to agree to buy anything online

3.5 A parent or guardian may submit a request to webmaster@proguitar.com to stop any further use of a child or young person’s personal Information or to request that we suppress any Information as far as we are able. Before disclosing Information about a child, we may request that the parent or guardian provide reasonable Information for identification purposes.

## 5 How we use your information

We will use your Information in the ways described below and as described at the time that the Information is collected.

### 5.1 To Provide the Services

In general, we use your Information as necessary or appropriate for our business purposes including to:

  * Administer your account where you have opened an account with us
  * Register you and provide you access to the website or services requested by you
  * Respond to inquiries or requests that you direct to us
  * Fulfil your requests for products or services
  * Send communications and administrative emails about the website or our services
  * Personalise and better tailor the features, performance and support of the website and our services for your use; analyse, benchmark and conduct research on user data and user interactions with the website and our services
  * Run competitions
  * Deliver customer services
  * Other purposes related to any of the above

### 5.2 Marketing

Where you have provided us with the appropriate consents we may send you marketing materials about other products or services offered by JR Innovation AB, including products or services offered by our group companies.

In addition, where you have provided us with the appropriate consents, we may also pass your Information for marketing purposes or host messages on behalf of one or more of our group companies or other selected third parties in the following sectors where the Information they provide will be relevant to you: Professional Associations, Automotive, Charity, Education and Training, Recruitment, Business and Leisure Travel, Events, Conferences and Exhibitions, Financial Services, Surveys and Research, Media, Broadcast and Marketing, Publishing and Subscriptions, Business and Information Services, Electronics, computers, Software and AV, Sports and Sportswear, Gaming, Betting, Telecoms and Retail and Partners and Sponsors of Promotions, Events and Competitions.

However, be assured that we understand the irritations of unsolicited communications and we are fully committed to ensuring the rights and obligations set out in applicable law. 

### 5.3 Behavioural Advertising – customer-relevant advertising

We believe that advertising is more interesting to you when it is relevant. Accordingly, we may customise the advertisements that you see based upon:

  * The Information you voluntarily provide to us
  * Geographic location Information, which we may determine through your IP address, from your mobile device, or other ways
  * Data we receive from third parties
  * Your visits to our website or your use of our services (commonly referred to as "Behavioural Advertising"). Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.proguitar.com/about/policies/cookies) for further Information.
  * Advertisers or other third parties using our website may also engage in Behavioural Advertising and use cookies and other technologies s in the manner in our Cookie Policy. We do not control these advertisers or other parties' use of cookies or other technologies or what they do with the Information they collect. Please see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.proguitar.com/about/policies/cookies) for further Information.

You can limit the way that we tailor advertising based on your Information by objecting to the cookies that we or third parties wish to place on your browser or deleting the cookies that we or third parties have placed on your browser. Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.proguitar.com/about/policies/cookies) for more details of how to delete cookies.

After you have exercised your right to object or reject the use of cookies, you may still see advertisements, but the advertising may not be as relevant to your interests. If you change your computer, change your browser or delete certain cookies, you will need to renew your preferences.

## 6 Correct or review your personal information

You can access, review, update and correct Personal Information you have provided us by clicking on the Edit Profile and/or Edit account link. If you prefer, you can also contact us by sending an email to webmaster@proguitar.com and explaining how you would like to modify your preferences.

## 7 How we disclose your information to third parties

We may share your Information with third parties as specifically approved by you or under the circumstances described below and in this Privacy Policy.

### 7.1 Disclosure for legal reasons

We may disclose your Information if we are under a duty to disclose or share your Information to comply with any legal obligation or in order to enforce or apply or fulfil our terms and conditions and other agreements or protect the rights, property, or safety of our customers, our group companies or others. This includes exchanging Information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

We use a number of third party organisations to help provide a professional service to our customers (i.e. fulfilment bureaus, call centres, and website designers). These organisations act as data processors and are strictly contractually controlled in how they may/may not use your Information and we remain responsible for the protection of your Information.

### 7.2 Promotions and Sponsors

Some or all of the Information collected during a promotion, contest or poll (“Promotions”) may be disclosed publicly. It may also be shared with other third parties as disclosed and consented to by you at the time of collection or in the Promotion rules. These third parties may include providers of prizes in order to update you of your status of your prize or other fulfilment needs or a co-sponsor who may use your Information to administer the Promotion or for their marketing purposes, but only in conformance with your consent, or with the terms published at the time your personal data is collected. We are not responsible for the privacy policy or practices of third parties.

When you participate in a Promotion, you are subject to any official rules for that Promotion, which may contain additional Information about the specific privacy practices associated with the Promotion.

### 7.3 Changes to our Company

In the event we go through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your Information may be among the assets transferred. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur and are permitted by this Privacy Policy.

### 7.4 Message Boards and Chats

We may make message boards, chat rooms, and other interactive forums available as part of our services. You should be aware that any Information which you post to these interactive forums or otherwise choose to make publicly available, may be disclosed and available to all users who have access to that portion of our website or services. By using these interactive forums, you agree that we are not responsible for any Information that you disclose or communicate in such forums, and any disclosures you make are at your own risk.

## 8 Updating and control of your information

There are a number of ways in which you can control the collection, use, and sharing of your Information and update your Information and preferences.

### 8.1 Opting-Out on Receipt of Marketing Communications

When you receive electronic marketing communications from us you will have the opportunity to "opt-out" by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in e-mails covering any marketing communication from us.

### 8.2 Preference Services

The Telephone Preference Service (TPS), the Corporate Telephone Preference Service (CTPS) and the Mailing Preference Service (MPS) allow you to choose to opt out of unsolicited marketing contact. However, if you are registered on any of the preference services, which are general opt-out registers, you may still receive marketing communications from us if you have given us your consent previously or if you subsequently give us that consent. 

### 8.3 Contacting Us

If your Information has changed or if you no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us then you can amend your Information. Please note that:

  * Even if you delete Information, we may retain your Information in conformance with our data retention policy most specifically for legal and tax reasons and to honour your opt-out requests; and
  * We do not keep Information longer than we deem necessary.
  * We are not responsible for updating or removing your Information contained in the lists or databases of third parties who have previously been provided with Information as permitted by this Privacy Policy.

## 9 Third party links and services

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website or you request a service from a third party, our Privacy Policy no longer applies. Your browsing and interaction on any other website or your dealings with any other third party service provider, is subject to that website’s or third party service provider’s own rules and policies. We do not monitor, control, or endorse the Information collection or privacy practices of any third parties. We encourage you to become familiar with the privacy practices of every website you visit or third party service provider that you deal with and to contact them if you have any questions about their respective privacy policies and practices. This Privacy Policy applies solely to Information collected by us through our website or services and does not apply to these third party websites and third party service providers.

## 10 Where we store your information

The Information that we collect from you may be transferred to, stored and processed at a destination outside the European Economic Area, (all EU countries plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein). Your Information may also be processed by staffs operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers, for instance, for customer service purposes. By submitting Information to us, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all reasonable steps necessary to ensure that your Information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## 11 Security of your information

We follow appropriate security procedures in the storage and disclosure of your Information so as to prevent unauthorised access by third parties. We also require those parties to whom we transfer personal Information to comply with the same. However, unfortunately, the transmission of Information via the Internet is not completely secure. So, we cannot ensure the security of your Information transmitted by you to us via the internet. Any such transmission is at your own risk and you acknowledge and agree that we shall not be responsible for any unauthorised use, distribution, damage or destruction of your Information. Once we have received your Information we will use security procedures and features to prevent unauthorised access to it.

## 12 Reporting of security vulnerabilities

Pro Guitar is committed to the privacy, safety and security of our customers. If you discover a potential security vulnerability, we would appreciate it if you could report it just to us in a responsible manner. Please email us at webmaster@proguitar.com and we will respond to you as soon as possible. This provides us with an opportunity to work with you and quickly address and resolve any issue. Publicly disclosing a potential vulnerability could put the wider community at risk, and therefore we encourage you to come to us first. We’ll keep you informed as we move forward with our investigations.

## 13 SOCIAL MEDIA

13.1 Pro Guitar provides users with the ability to use their social media credentials to sign in to our website(s) 

When you create your Pro Guitar account, and authenticate via a third-party service such as Google, Twitter, LinkedIn or Facebook, you grant permission to the social network to share your user details with us. Depending on the network this will include

  * Basic account Information included in your public profile such as name and email address required to verify and facilitate your sign in
  * Other Information that is publically available based upon the privacy settings you have with your social media account.
  * Any other details you choose to share according to your specific account settings.

We will be clear when we do request more than just basic account Information from you and request that you should also check what permissions we are asking for before you connect with these apps and services. We want to use this Information to better tailor any content we provide to you.

13.2 Social networking sites, such as Facebook, Linked-In, among others, work with us as trusted third party partners. We also work with application developers who specialise in social media, so that we can connect with your social networks. We provide access to our Websites for third parties and business partners so that we can generate interest in our products and services among members of your social networks and to allow you to share product and service interests with friends in your network.

13.3 We do not control how your personal Information is collected, stored or used by such third party sites or to whom it is disclosed. You should review the privacy policies and settings on any social networking site that you subscribe to so that you understand the Information they may be sharing. If you do not want your networking sites to share Information about you, you must contact that site and determine whether it gives you the opportunity to opt-out of sharing such Information. Pro Guitar is not responsible for how these third party sites may use Information collected from or about you.

## 14 Anti-spam policy

Pro Guitar provides exciting and thought-provoking content in our emails and aims to tailor them to the specific needs & interests of our brand audiences. We hope you enjoy receiving and reading them.

Pro Guitar has zero tolerance concerning the sending of unsolicited/bulk commercial email - “spam”. In respect of this policy, please also refer to our [Cookies Policy](https://www.proguitar.com/about/policies/cookies).

### 14.1 Automated Spam Filtering

We automatically scan all incoming electronic messages and filter out those that appear to be spam. As no system can be 100% accurate in detecting genuine emails from spam, authentic messages may occasionally be filtered. If you believe this may have happened, please contact the recipient by another means.

### 14.2 Unwanted messages from Pro Guitar

Any recipient of email communication from us may request, at any time, to unsubscribe. In the unlikely event you are in receipt of email communication from Pro Guitar which could be considered as spam, we encourage you to report it to us by forwarding a copy to us at: webmaster@proguitar.com

We will fully investigate any reports of abuse.

## 15 How to contact us

If you have any questions or complaints about our Privacy Policy, you can contact our customer service department at webmaster@proguitar.com. When we receive such inquiries about our Privacy Policy, we will use the Personal Information (such as your email address) only to respond to your question or comment. However, if your question raises one or more issues that affect our promotional partners, we may also share your question with them in order to provide a response.

## 16 Changes in This Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify, alter or otherwise update this Privacy Policy at any time, so we encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we make changes that we consider material in our privacy practices, we will notify you in this space. We may also attempt to notify you of any such material changes to our privacy practices via email or by placing a notice on our home page.

## 17 Acceptance of This Privacy Policy

By using this Service, you consent to the collection and use of your Personal Information by Pro Guitar in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
